A Guide to the Charles McDowell Papers, 1944-2004
Library of Virginia
- Series II. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1944-2004., Extent: 25 boxes. (Box 10-34)
  - Watergate Revisited - WETA, 1994. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Watergate (Sam Ervin). (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - WETA Channel 26. (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - White House "Insiders". (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Whitehurst, G. William. (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Wilson Wyatt Narration - Louisville PBS, 1994. (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Wiretapping - Fairfax Chief Durrer. (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Woodrow Wilson Birthplace Advisory Council. (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - World Bank. (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Writing - Tips, Pointers, etc.. (Box 34, Folder 20-21)
  - Young, Stephen M.. (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Zoo. (Box 34, Folder 23)
- Series III. Books and Videotapes., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 35-36)
  The collection contains numerous books presented to McDowell that contain inscriptions by the authors.
  Videotapes in the collection include many of McDowell's appearances on "For the Record," as well as programs which he narrated, including "Summer of Judgment: The Watergate Hearings," "The James: Revolutionary River," and "Richmond Memories." There are also taped interviews with McDowell, speeches, and other appearances.
  - Red Barber. 1947: When All Hell Broke Loose in Baseball. (De Capo Press, 1982). (Box 35)
  - Harry F. Byrd, Jr. Double Trouble: Vignettes from a Life in Politics and Newspapering (Harrisonburg, Va.: RR Donnelley and Sons, 2007). (Box 35)
  - Bruce Chadwick. The Reel Civil War: Mythmaking in American Film. (New York: Knopf, 2001). (Box 35)
  - Paul Duke, ed. Beyond Reagan: The Politics of Upheaval. (New York: Warner Books, 1986). (Box 35)
  - Kent M. Keith. Anyway: The Paradoxical Commandments. (New York: G. P. Putnam's Sons, 2001). (Box 35)
  - C. Brian Kelly. Best Little Stories from the White House. (Charlottesville, Va: Montpelier Publishing, 1992). (Box 35)
  - Florence Selden Peple. The Red and White Secret. (Richmond, Va.: Garrett & Massie, 1931). (Box 35)
  - A.J.G. Priest. Old Hilarity. (Charlottesville, Va.: The Michie Company, 1965). (Box 35)
  - William W. Pusey III. Washington and Lee University in Fiction. (1988). (Box 35)
  - Parke Shepherd Rouse, Jr. [Collected Stories, 1997?]. (Box 35)
  - William D. Rouse. Plucked Again! (Writers Club Press, 2000). (Box 35)
  - Cassette - David Broder, Julie Johnson, and Charles McDowell. "Election, '96: Let the Games Begin." Ford Hall Forum, Faneuil Hall, Boston, 3 November 1995. (Box 36)
  - Cassette - Toast to Hugh Haynie, Society of Professional Journalists, 26 June 1996. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - Gridiron Club Dinner (Beta), 1982. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "Summer of Judgment: The Watergate Hearings" (Two Copies) 1983. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "Outlook," Demo, Potomac Television Productions, Inc., Washington, DC, 1983. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - Gridiron Club Dinner (Beta), 1984. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "Free Speech and Advertising - Who Draws the Line?" Institute for Democratic Communication, Boston University, 1987. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - Charles McDowell Being Inducted into the Virginia Communications Hall of Fame, 1988. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - Centre College, Danville, KY Graduation, 1989. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "The James: Revolutionary River," 1990. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "Rally Behind the Virginians" with Charles McDowell (Program on land conservation/preservation), 1994. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "Washington Journal," Charles McDowell Interview, C-SPAN, 4 September 1995. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "Former Offenders: Breaking the Cycle of Violence," Across the River with Hedrick Smith, WETA, October 1995. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "Richmond Memories" WCVE, 1995. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Charles McDowell," Interview by Ken Thompson, 18 October 1996. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "Virginia Vote '96 with Paul Duke" WCVE/WHTJ, 24 October 1996. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "More Richmond Memories" WCVE, 1996. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Margaret Warner," 10 October 1997. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - Charles McDowell and Shelby Foote, Fredericksburg Form, University of Mary Washington, 28 October 1997. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Linwood Holton" Part I, 28 November 1997. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Linwood Holton" Part II, 19 December 1997. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Stansfield Turner," 23 January 1998. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Gale Mattox," 27 February 1998. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Julian Bond," 24 April 1998. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Lowell Weicker," 27 April 1998. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Lee Hamilton," 26 June 1998. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Kathryn Thornton," 25 September 1998. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Lech Walesa," 16 October 1998. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: John Sununu," 21 November 1998. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "Richmond Memories: School Days" WCVE, 1998. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Timothy Naftali," 8 January 1999. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Bobby Muller," 12 February 1999. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Philip D. Zelikow," 26 March 1999. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Jim Jones," 9 April 1999. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - Washington and Lee 250th Anniversary National Day of Celebration Television Special, 1 May 1999. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - Washington and Lee 250th Anniversary Cruise, 1999. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "For the Record: Charles McDowell" Interview by Charles Sydnor, 24 March 2000. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "The Great Campaign of 1960." Off Center Productions and WETA, 30 October 2000. (Box 36)
  - Videotape - "Judy Garland: The Concert Years" (1985); Candidate Bill Clinton at Georgetown University, 23 October 1991; Miscellaneous Clips; "The Civil War: Episode Three" (clip); Dan Quayle on the Rush Limbaugh Show; Wimbledon Coverage.. (Box 36)